Edward Hartman

Senior Full Stack & Blockchain Engineer



- mike.dragon0905@gmail.com
- +1 786 347 1994
- github.com/NikeDragon0905
- S live:.cid.db7376c3cccdf9af
- in linkedin.com/in/edwardhartman0905
- 1525 W Koenig Ln, Brentwood, Austin, Texas, US
- Male
- **## 05/09/1996**

PROFILE

I am an experienced senior full-stack engineer who has been mainly focusing on JavaScript, Python, C/C++ and Java to develop the products. During the last 8+ years, I have worked in many companies to build applications for people all over the world. As an active and innovative learner, I love learning programming languages and skills. I have rich experience in blockchain technologies and crypto currencies as well for DeFi application. I fully guarantee my code quality and I am eager to brainstorm a new idea with teammates. My goal is to offer more products that people would prefer.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Front End & Blockchain Engineer, *PowerUSD, LLC* 02/2022 – 02/2023

San Francisco, California, United States

- Mostly used modern JS frameworks such as React(Next),
 Vue.js(Nuxt) for Front-end development
- Developed smart contracts for decentralized lending platform on Ethereum blockchain and integrated with Front-end using web3
- Worked on Golang Backend API service
- Audited smart contracts for NFT tokens and sales on Polygon/Matic
- Ensured quality standards through regular code reviews of contractor's codebase contributions
- Tech Stack: React, Next, Vue.js, Nuxt, Blockchain, Web3, Ethereum, Golang, Polygon/Matic

Senior Full Stack Engineer, Golden Hippo

10/2020 - 02/2022

Woodland Hills, California, United States

- Worked with a team of senior web designers, full-stack engineers, and the QAs to meet project goals and create effective user experiences for millions of subscribers
- Developed full-stack applications across various platforms using the latest industry-adopted technologies, microservices and frameworks
- Worked using CMS Frameworks and no-coding platforms
- Ported the underlying deprecated Ionic library to Webpack 5, speeding up local and remote builds by up to six times
- Participated in the development of API for payment between B2B, B2C, and C2C
- Accumulated sufficient experience related to the operation and management of the e-commerce platform.
- Worked on an agile team and presented my idea for the product to CTO at the scrum meeting
- Tech Stack: TypeScript, Vue.js, Nuxt, React, React Native, Flutter, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Restful APIs, Stripe API, GraphQL, .NET, Microservices, WordPress, Shopify

Full Sack Developer, Coding Dojo

12/2019 - 10/2020 | Dallas, Texas, United States

 Developed dynamic and interactive websites that ensured high traffic, page views, and user experience, resulting in 40% increase in sales revenue

SKILLS

Information Technology ● ● ● ● ● (IT)

- Programming and coding HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Python, C/C++, Java, NodeJS, Kotlin
- Networking and Security
 Knowledge of networking protocols and technologies,
 Information security principles,
 Cybersecurity tools and techniques
- Database management
 MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB,
 Oracle, ElasticSearch
- Web Development
 React, Vue.js, Angular
 CSS Frameworks, CMS Frameworks
- Mobile App Development Android, iOS, React Native, Flutter
- System administration Windows, MacOS, Linux, Unix
- DevOps: CI/CD, IAC, Monitoring & Feedback
- Blockchain Smart Contract, Token, Ethereum, Crypto Currency
- Others
- * Communication & Collaboration
- * Problem-solving
- * Continuous learning

Design

- Graph Design
- UX/UI Design
- Web Design
- Packaging Design

- Oversaw the full lifecycle of software development for 4 projects with 100% on-time delivery while staying 5% under budget
- Added to the company database of code by developing reusable code that could minimize the time needed to maintain the projects
- Designed and developed product details page by using React for user interface, SASS, Material UI for styling, and Redux for state management
- Implemented server with various databases (RDBMS and NoSQL) for retrieving the data in the form of JSON using AJAX
- Used Git version control for the source code management of the application
- Tech Stack: React, Vue.js, Angular, SASS, ExpressJS, Python, Laravel, REST, AWS, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AWS

Intern Web & Mobile App Developer, Forest Company 05/2017 – 12/2019 | Tai Po, Hong Kong

- Built several web & mobile applications using React,
 Angular, React Native, Flutter, and Android frameworks
- Designed the Web application layout and forms
- Handled all the client-side validations, slide show, hide/show controls, dropdown menus, and tab navigation using jQuery
- Created application-level code to perform client-side validations using jQuery and JavaScript
- Experienced in building mobile applications for various type of devices
- Used SVN for version control and defect tracking
- Worked on cross-browser compatibility issues and fix the bugs pertaining to various browsers
- Pair programmed with 4 engineers and reviewed the team's code to provide additional perspective and catch previously missed errors
- Tech Stack: React, Angular, React Native, Flutter, Android, Tailwind CSS JavaScript, jQuery, Restful API, GraphQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL

EDUCATION

National University of Singapore,

Bachelor of Computer Science (BCompSc)

2013 – 2017 | Singapore, Singapore GPA: 3.8/3.9

CERTIFICATES

- IBM Blockchain Foundation for Developer Certificate by Coursera in 2021
- Full-stack Web and Multiplatform App Development Certificate by Coursera in 2020
- Front-end Web Development Certificate by Coursera in 2019
- NodeJS-The Complete Guide (MVC, REST APIs, GraphQL) by Udemy in 2018
- HTML5 Web Developer Camp Certificate by Coursera in 2018
- React-The Complete Guide (Hooks, React, Router, Redux) by Udemy in 2017
- Introduction to Programming Using JavaScript by Udemy in 2017

COURSES

Network Fundamentals and Protocols,

National University of Singapore 2013 – 2015 | Singapore, Singapore

This course covered the fundamentals of network security, including common threats, vulnerabilities, and attack vectors, as well as methods for mitigating and preventing security breaches.

Topics covered included access control, encryption, firewalls, intrusion detection and prevention, and security policies and procedures.

Through hands-on labs and projects, I gained experience in configuring and securing network devices, analyzing network traffic for security threats, and developing security policies and procedures.

This course has equipped me with the knowledge and skills to identify and mitigate security risks, ensure data confidentiality and integrity, and comply with industry-standard security practices.

Project Management Fundamentals,

National University of Singapore

2014 – 2017 | Singapore, Singapore

This course provided an overview of project management methodologies and best practices, including project planning, execution, monitoring, and control.

Topics covered included stakeholder management, risk assessment, budgeting, and resource allocation. The course also emphasized effective communication and leadership skills for project managers.

Through various group projects and case studies, I gained hands-on experience in project management techniques and tools, and developed the ability to manage competing priorities and deadlines.

This course has equipped me with the knowledge and skills to lead successful projects and collaborate effectively with cross-functional teams.

LANGUAGES

English		
IELTS		
Chinoso		

INTERESTS

Tennis

I am an avid amateur tennis player with a competitive skills. I have also volunteered at various events and have experience playing matches with all ages.

Memorization

Number memorization is a fun and enjoyable activity, so I don't put too much pressure on myself to remember everything perfectly. Just have fun and challenge myself to improve over time!